My Father Broke His Leg Over 20 Times.
How Can I Help Him?
My family was very poor
when I was growing up.
My parents sent me away
to another home,
But there I was
severely abused.
I wondered why
I had to suffer so much,
When I was getting beaten.
I thought I would die, If I didn't
understand the reason for my suffering.
I thought, "why do I have to suffer?
Is it because of my sins in my past lives?"
(Sunim) No, you can't think that way.
(Sunim) You could instead think,
"They hit me, but at least they feed me."
(Audience Laugh)
(Sunim) Other people
didn't beat you or feed you.
(Sunim) They at least fed you
even though they beat you.
(Questioner)
I never thought that way,
(Questioner) But I did try to understand
my experience in my own way.
As you said, I examined myself,
And I could understand
Other people's behavior as
I see them in myself too.
Buddha talked about karma.
My father got very little education.
He didn't even finish elementary school.
He injured his leg once,
but it kept breaking over 20 times.
The same leg kept breaking.
The hospital bills are a lot to handle,
but I still want to help my father.
Every time his leg breaks,
he becomes immobile.
He can't work,
so he feels frustrated.
I can take care of myself, but
when I watch my father
Getting old and more deteriorated,
I suffer.
How can I help him?
(Sunim) There's nothing
you can do to help.
That is your problem.
Your father is doing fine.
He's in pain,
but he's living on.
You are the one who's
feeling bad about it.
Your feeling sorry for him
doesn't help him at all.
If you're sad and stressed about it,
it makes him feel worse.
That is your father's life.
(Sunim) In autumn, leaves
fall from trees, yes?
(Sunim) Some people feel sad
when the leaves fall, right?
Don't they?
Feeling sad about the falling leaves
Whose problem is that?
The leaves or the person?
(Questioner)
The person.
Right. So feeling bad about your dad
Is that his problem or your problem?
(Questioner)
My dad's problem.
(Sunim and Audience Laugher)
(Questioner) It's his,
but since he's my dad…
(Sunime) No.
It's your problem,
not your dad's.
(Questioner) But the
thing about karma…
Then, that student who was crying
over her dead brother,
Is that his problem or hers?
(Questioner)
It's hers.
You say that crying over her dead brother
is her problem, but not your dad?
But feeling bad about your dad
is not your problem?
(Questioner)
well, I don't cry
(Questioner) But my dad keeps
getting hurt, so his karma…
Normally, if you break your leg,
you'd be crippled.
But your dad broke
his leg 20 times.
That means he was able to fix it 20 times.
He's living in a good time.
If he could recover 20 times,
that means he's not crippled.
(Questioner)
He can't walk.
That's still okay.
He was able to fix it 20 times
because he could.
If he had been born a long time ago,
Would he have been able to
fix his leg 20 times?
Instead of worrying about
his leg breaking 20 times,
think about it healing 20 times.
They are the same situation.
If that's his karma,
is there a way to undo it?
(Sunim) It's because
he has weak legs.
(Questioner and
Audience Laugher)
(Questioner) So should I
get him to exercise?
For example, he may have osteoporosis.
His bones are weak.
(Questioner) My dad is
kind of obese…
It's because his weak legs
can't support his weight.
(Sunim) If he breaks the leg again,
he can fix it again.
(Questioner) Okay.
(Audience Appause)
You pose this question seriously,
but I answer lightheartedly.
You can't cry over spilled milk.
Be positive about things
that had already happened.
Even about death, how can we take it?
We can take it as a good thing.
Do you understand?
Let's say when you were young,
our family was poor and you were
raised by another family.
Even your parents, when they're
dealing with such poverty,
Could have mistreated you, right?
They could.
So, when you're to raise
another person's child,
Could you mistreat her?
They probably didn't think
of it as child abuse.
(Sunim) They probably thought
they were just getting upset.
From their point of view, they raised
another person's child
And still got criticized.
Is that foolish or what?
You should never raise
someone else's child.
You'll always be criticized.
(Audience Laugher)
So, how should you
think about this situation
Once you've become an adult?
You could think that
they still raised you.
They mistreated you
at times,
But they gave you
food and shelter.
If you can feel grateful for that,
your suffering will end.
"I can be thankful for them."
But when you were young,
you thought only about their abuse.
If their abuse was
about 10,
Their efforts in raising you
is about 100.
You could think that way
and be grateful.
That's how you can get healed.
Likewise, your father's leg's
breaking 20 times.
After the 10th time,
you'd think he's jinxed.
Don't take it that way.
The problem is that
your dad is obese,
And his legs are weak.
Repeated injuries in the
same place mean that
These individual injuries
were not entirely serious.
(Sunim) When I was in jail,
(Sunim) My cellmate had 16
criminal convictions.
I was scared out of my mind.
16 convictions!
He was quite young too.
I was really scared of him, but
when I got to know him,
He was an ordinary person.
Why? To be convicted
16 times,
Do you commit serious crimes
or petty crimes?
You get convicted 16 times
only for petty crimes.
If you murder or seriously
assault someone,
You go to jail forever
after the first offence, right?
16 convictions seem
really serious,
But they're only
petty thefts.
(Audience Laughter)
(Sunim) Only petty thieves
can get convicted 16 times.
So you should not
misunderstand it.
If he broke his leg really seriously,
would it be there to break again?
No. Breaking 20 times
means that
The leg suffered
minor injuries.
He would break the leg 20 times
only if these were minor breaks.
If it were a serious break,
it couldn't have broken 20 times.
It all happened because he was
overweight with weak bones.
It's not a curse.
(Sunim) It all depends on
how you look at it.
(Sunim)
So don't worry.
How old is he?
(Sunim) 65
There are people with missing limbs
or with prosthetics, right?
So it's okay.
You know where
you should go?
You should attend a gathering of
physically handicapped people.
Everything is relative.
That's how we humans think.
Let's say I was on a bus
with 30 other people,
Then there was an accident
and you broke your arm.
You're unlucky, right?
You had bad luck
And broke your arm.
But when you look around,
Everyone else is dead
and you're the only survivor.
(Audience Laughter)
(Sunim) Then are you
lucky or unlucky?
You're extremely lucky.
You see?
Or, you look around,
and nobody else got hurt.
Then what happens?
You call yourself unlucky.
So breaking a leg or
an arm in itself is
Neither lucky nor unlucky.
We judge depending on how the
situation compares to other people's.
Our perception determines
whether an event is lucky or unlucky.
So how should we
perceive things?
Things themselves are
neither good luck nor bad luck.
They were neither
good nor bad.
We call that emptiness.
But people tend to
think negatively
About everything that
happens to them.
So they're always unhappy.
I always think positively
about everything.
I think everything
happened out of luck.
(Sunim) This is an
extreme example:
(Sunim) If you hurt one leg
going down the stairs,
You would grab your leg
and think,
"What a bad luck!
Oh, my leg?!"
But I would grab
my other leg
And say, "Wow, this one
didn't break!"
(Audience Laughter
and Applause)
It's better than breaking
both legs, right?
The Bible says,
If anyone forces you to go one mile,
go with them two miles.
If anyone asks for your shirt,
hand over your coat as well.
Don't be a slave to a
given situation.
Own your choices and be positive.
Think positively.
Think positively about things
that already happened.
The situation will
remain the same,
But you'll always
feel hopeful.
You're unhappy not because
unhappy things happen.
You're unhappy because
you look at things negatively.
That's why you're
always unhappy.
Take your karma of negativity,
And change it to karma of positivity.
(Sunim) Practice that.